MEHDI AMHMUD

Web developer



mehdi.mahmud@hotmail.com



07511118806



https://mehdimahmud79.github.io/ProfessionalPortfolio



Birmingham, Halesowen, B63 2TQ

ABOUT ME

Full-stack developer with a passion for coding and problem solving situated in Birmingham. I hold a PhD in applied mathematics from University of Birmingham. Experience in doing researcher, teaching, IT, and professional video editing.

Linked in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mehdi-mahmud/

GitHub



https://github.com/mehdimahmud79



https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Mehdi-Mahmud

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF BIRMINGHAM

[2015-2020]

PhD applied Mathematics

UNIVERSITY OF BIRMINGHAM

[May2021-Nov2021]

Certificate in Full Stack web Development from (Currently working towards)

UNIVERSITY OF Salahaddin-Iraq/Erbil

[2007-2009]

Msc. applied Mathematics

UNIVERSITY OF Salahaddin-Iraq/Erbil

[1998-2002]

Bsc. Mathematics

OBJECTIVES

A skilled programmer can adapt to all stages of advanced programming. Capable of coding, user interface, testing, and debugging procedures. Full-stack developer with a passion for coding and problem solving situated in Birmingham. I hold a PhD in applied mathematics from the University of Birmingham and since 2001, I have been experienced in doing research, teaching, IT, and video editing. Currently expanding my expertise by enrolling in an intense Full-Stack Bootcamp at the University of Birmingham, which will be completed in November 2021.

✓ TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML• CSS• JavaScript jQuery Express.js Sequelize •
 Handlebars Node.js Jest GitHub Tailwind Bootsraps
 Express Sessions
- Languages / Frameworks Learning
- React MongoDB Passport
- Other programming Languages
- Fortran Matlab VisualBasic
- **↓** IDE/ Tools
- VS Code Insomnia Notepad++

OTHER SKILLS

• Microsoft Office • Adobe Premier • 3D Software(Abagus)

✓ PROJECTS

Movie Time

https://movietimeuk.herokuapp.com/

Employee Tracker

https://mehdimahmud79.github.io/Employee-Tracker/

Weather Dashboard

https://mehdimahmud79.github.io/WeatherDashboard/

- **Find all of my projects at:**
- https://mehdimahmud79.github.io/ProfessionalPortfolio

EXPERIENCE

Research Fellow/University of Birmingham

Sep 2019- 30th May 2021

Research project: Maximising cavitation to clean dental implants, EPSRC Grant

University of Birmingham

2015-2019

Teaching assistant- part time- during my PhD study.

Ass.Lecturer/ Sallahaddin Uni./Erbil 2009-2014

Assistant lecturer at Mathematics Department / College of Science /Salahaddin University/Erbil/IRAQ.

Teaching ass. / Sallahaddin Uni./Erbil 2003-2007

Teaching assistant-Full time- at Mathematics Department / College of Science /Salahaddin University/Erbil/IRAQ.

Video editor/IT

2000-2014

Part time job as IT and video editor at Zagros tv and Gulan TV in Erbil.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

- Advanced Calculus, Mathematics Department, Salahaddin University-Erbil-Iraq., 2012- 2014
- Latex Package, Mathematics Department, Salahaddin University-Erbil-Iraq., 2013
- Numerical Analysis, Mathematics Department, Salahaddin University-Erbil-Iraq., 2010, 2014
- Visual Basic programming, Mathematics Department, Salahaddin University-Erbil-Iraq., 2010-2012.
- Visual Basic programming, Mathematics Department, Salahaddin University-Soran-Iraq., 2008-2010.
- Computational Mathematics using Matlab, Mathematics Department, Salahaddin University-Erbil-Iraq, IT Department in Lebanese French University-Erbil, 2013-2007,

PUBLICATIONS

- Wang, Q., Mahmud, M., Cui, J., Smith, W.R. and Walmsley, A.D., 2020. Numerical investigation of bubble dynamics at a corner. *Physics of Fluids*, *32*(5), p.053306.
- Vyas, N., Mahmud, M., Wang, Q.X. and Walmsley, A.D., 2020. Imaging and Quantification of the Area of Fast-Moving Microbubbles Using a High-Speed Camera and Image Analysis. JoVE (Journal of Visualized Experiments), (163), p.e61509.
- Rostam K. Saeed and Mehdi H. Mahmud, Solution of a system of two-dimensional linearFredholm integral equation of the second kind by quadrature methods, *Australian Journal of Basic and Applied Sciences*, Vol.3, No.3 (2009), 1701-1715.
- Mehdi H. Mahmud and Rostam K. Saeed, Numerical Solution of System of Two-DimensionalLinear Fredholm Integral Equations of the Second Kind by Adomian Decomposition Method, Proceeding of the 4th International scientific conference of Salahaddin University-Erbil,October 18-20, Vol.1 of 4 (2011), 31-34.fa

RESEARCH INTEREST

- ♣ Bubble dynamics; Modeling Cavitation
- Boundary integral method
- Numerical Modeling; Computational Fluid Dynamics.
- Abaqus ; Modeling Cavitation around ultrasonic dental scaler.